# Maathusan Rajendram

**PROGRAM** 2B Systems Design Engineering 08 Ozark Court • Brampton, Ontario • L6Y 0L4

CELL (519) 574-0728 • E-MAIL mrajendr@uwaterloo.ca • WEBSITE www.matraj.cu.cc

#### PROFILE

Strong understanding of object-oriented programming concepts and their application.

Love the startup culture and working in an extremely fast-paced environment; from previous co-op experiences.

Great communication, presentation and interpersonal skills.

Perfectionist for user interface and design; detail-oriented.

## **EDUCATION**

# Candidate for Bachelor of Applied Science

Systems Design Engineering, University of Waterloo, Waterloo, ON September 2012-present

## SKILLS

Objective - C Swift

C#/C++ HTML/CSS Java

Ruby on Rails Adobe Photoshop JavaScript/jQuery

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## iOS App Developer

ERA Environmental Consulting • Montreal, Quebec • April 2014 – August 2014

Created and deployed two iOS 7 universal apps into the App store (see website). Created a WCF REST web service in C# for the above apps to communicate with MS SQL Server. Worked on and deployed an iPad app via In-house distribution. Worked on a Ruby on Rails web service that connected the iPad app to a PostgreSQL database.

# iOS App Developer

Sangriya Inc. • Brampton, Ontario • August 2013 – February 2014

Created an iOS 7 app with search, chat, notification, filter, Facebook login and more features; from conception. Contributed to marketing and analytics analysis. Made use of Facebook API's, Parse platform, Testflight, Crashlytics and Mixpanel Analytics.

# **Program Management**

**Toronto Hydro •** Toronto, Ontario • January 2013 – May 2013

Used thorough knowledge of SQL, VBA, normalization and UI development to create a relational database in a MS Access environment. Acquired presentation

and communication skills from presenting program management issues in front of project manager and his team.

# **Marketing Representative**

**Student Works Painting** • Waterloo, Ontario • May 2013 – August 2013

Utilized excellent communication and marketing skills to make door-to-door sales. Acquired amazing marketing techniques from training sessions. Gained amazing time management and organizational skills from balancing two part-time jobs and school work.

#### VOLUNTEER

#### Tutor

Club Garcons et Filles de LaSalle • Montreal, Quebec • April 2014 – June 2014

Tutored student ranging from the ages of 9 to 16 in Mathematics, Science and English. Improved my communication skills in French.

#### **Chefs Assistant**

Robin des Bois • Montreal, Quebec • June 2014 – August 2014

Helped prepare ingredients and assisted in all prep work for the dishes. Improved my communication skills in French.

# Supervisor

**Epilepsy Halton Peel Hamilton** • Brampton, Ontario • November 2013 – January 2014 Promoted from volunteer to supervisor within two weeks. Successfully lead and was responsible for a team of 18 volunteers.